<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Learning on timpieces</title><link>https://timpieces.me/tags/learning/</link><description>Recent content in Learning on timpieces</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://timpieces.me/tags/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>pubschool</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/pubschool/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/pubschool/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A good friend that I met in Singapore decided to move to the UK. It was a shame, but as an expat in Singapore it&amp;rsquo;s expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a going away celebration, I joked that I would teach him how to act in a British pub. He&amp;rsquo;s from the US and doesn&amp;rsquo;t drink, and the thought was that he&amp;rsquo;d have to get comfortable in British pubs as it&amp;rsquo;s such a significant part of the culture.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>mandarin</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/mandarin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/mandarin/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In late 2023 I was looking for a new hobby in Singapore. Ideally one where I can meet people and it&amp;rsquo;s different to things I have tried in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought about it for a while and realised that Mandarin should be a good fit. It&amp;rsquo;s the second most useful language to know in Singapore, and there are plenty of places offering classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had done some French duolingo before, but otherwise had no experience learning a language.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>learning programming</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/learning-programming/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/learning-programming/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;(Note: I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure how to date this entry, as I&amp;rsquo;ve never really stopped programming. I decided to focus it around my initial year or two of learning programming as it provides the most insight into the endeavour. I may split out more endeavours as it&amp;rsquo;s been such an important part of my life)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember as a young teenager always wanting to understand how technology really worked. In previous decades, I think that this led people to become fascinated with cars. I had been playing games on our family&amp;rsquo;s computer since I was 6, so I gravitated towards computers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>