<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Health on timpieces</title><link>https://timpieces.me/tags/health/</link><description>Recent content in Health on timpieces</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://timpieces.me/tags/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>yoga</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/yoga/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/yoga/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I chose yoga because it was so different to any hobbies that I had tried before. Also, it was near my apartment.
Yoga Movement is a very commercial yoga chain in Singapore. I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of what they&amp;rsquo;ve done to commoditize yoga, as I&amp;rsquo;m not sold on the spiritual side of yoga. I downloaded their app and booked some classes.
I did the basic class many many times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without trying to sound bitter, yoga seems like an activity designed mostly for women&amp;rsquo;s bodies. They seem to have a much better level of default flexibility, which makes it much more enjoyable. It&amp;rsquo;s achievable for men (evidenced by the male yogis at the studio), but it seems to take much more effort.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gym</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/gym/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/gym/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Starting a gym routine in late 2021 was one of the most impactful changes in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing up I was always very skeptical of gyms and resistance training. It seemed very vain and an expensive way to get exercise.
During covid I tried some at-home calisthenics. It seemed more stimulating than training at a gym. While learning about the basics of calisthenics I became more aware of the benefits of a gym. This learning coupled with encouragement and guidance from a friend led me to try a single session, followed by a two-week trial, followed by a (now 4+ year) membership.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>