<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fitness on timpieces</title><link>https://timpieces.me/tags/fitness/</link><description>Recent content in Fitness on timpieces</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://timpieces.me/tags/fitness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>running</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/running/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/running/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a reluctant runner for my whole life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a kid, we were forced to do cross-country training. Noone ever explained to me that running is supposed to be uncomfortable, and so I was terrible at it. Being terrible at something as a kid is a surefire way to hate it the rest of your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In late high-school I was overweight, and I took up some running to lose weight. It worked and I got down to a healthy weight (although still not &amp;lsquo;slim&amp;rsquo;). But I never got interested in running itself, and I doubt I surpassed 5km.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>cycling</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/cycling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/cycling/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve never had a strong interest in the &amp;lsquo;art of cycling&amp;rsquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ve never even watched a Tour de France stage. I like cycling because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Riding fast downhill is thrilling (while feeling relatively safe)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s good, low-impact exercise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It came to me at a time in life when I had forgotten how important hobbies are&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first two points are self-explanatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018 I had been focusing on my career to the exclusion of everything else. I slept on a mattress on the floor, owned very little, and had no hobbies. I would spend the weekend relaxing, drinking, socialising, playing the odd video game. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t a fulfilling life.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>gym</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/gym/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/gym/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Starting a gym routine in late 2021 was one of the most impactful changes in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing up I was always very skeptical of gyms and resistance training. It seemed very vain and an expensive way to get exercise.
During covid I tried some at-home calisthenics. It seemed more stimulating than training at a gym. While learning about the basics of calisthenics I became more aware of the benefits of a gym. This learning coupled with encouragement and guidance from a friend led me to try a single session, followed by a two-week trial, followed by a (now 4+ year) membership.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>