<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Craft on timpieces</title><link>https://timpieces.me/tags/craft/</link><description>Recent content in Craft on timpieces</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://timpieces.me/tags/craft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>3d printing</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/3d-printing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/3d-printing/</guid><description>Learning 3d modelling and printing</description></item><item><title>homebrew</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/homebrew/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/homebrew/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="./homebrew.jpg" alt="homebrew"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least in Australia, it seems that every middle-aged man tries brewing his own beer at some point in his life.
With the knowledge that I&amp;rsquo;m likely to follow in that path one day, but that I have some time off of work in 2025, I figured why not get it out of the way now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought a kit online, and a fridge to control the fermentation temperature in Singapore&amp;rsquo;s yeast-unfriendly weather. The kit was a partial mash, and I enjoyed the brewing process, so I found my local homebrew store and bought some more gear and ingredients for another.
After the first two brews, I tried to make some cider with a friend. We bought some cheap green apples from the supermarket and manually cut, blended, and squeezed them. Despite the very adhoc process, the cider actually turned out quite decent (but very sour).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>crochet</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/crochet/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/crochet/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I bought a crochet kit from a bookstore in Singapore. It was a Harry Potter kit. I completely butchered Harry but it was enough to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I figured that the best way to learn would be to learn with other people. As a frequent user of Meetup, I resolved to finally create my own group and see what it&amp;rsquo;s like to be an organiser. As silly as it sounds, this was quite a big step for me. I&amp;rsquo;d never been good at organising social events, and had been brought up to be quite horrified of this idea.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>