<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Music on timpieces</title><link>https://timpieces.me/tags/music/</link><description>Recent content in Music on timpieces</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://timpieces.me/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>guitar</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/guitar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/guitar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the exact reason that I decided to give the guitar a shot.
Probably my feeling was that it&amp;rsquo;s provides the best ratio of impact to effort of any instrument. You can have played piano or violin for years, yet an audience will still gravitate to a dudebro with 6 months of guitar experience. Plus, guitars are often just lying around. It&amp;rsquo;s quite rare to stumble across a piano that you can just play. So guitar felt like a useful skill to have.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>piano</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/piano/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/piano/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="childhood"&gt;childhood&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did a year or two of keyboard lessons in primary school. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember much about it except that I hardly practiced outside of lessons (every poor student&amp;rsquo;s downfall).
I gave it up either because I was no longer enjoying it or my parents didn&amp;rsquo;t like paying for something that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t practicing (reasonable).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="university"&gt;university&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had an itch to pick it back up again during my gap year, and I continued playing during university. I bought a second hand piano from an online marketplace for a few hundred dollars.
I decided not to pay a teacher (mostly because I&amp;rsquo;m cheap). And while I think I wasn&amp;rsquo;t so consistent, I actually clocked quite a few hours of practice over the years. I learned some Chopin and some Scott Joplin, and improved my music theory a lot. I even practiced scales and did some other drills.
I never really had the discipline to get &amp;lsquo;properly good&amp;rsquo; or perform, but I got a lot of value out of learning and practicing the basics. Definitely enough that I don&amp;rsquo;t require the expenses involved or the time spent.
I gradually practiced less and less over the coming years, and sold the piano when I moved away from Perth.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>