<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Social on timpieces</title><link>https://timpieces.me/tags/social/</link><description>Recent content in Social on timpieces</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://timpieces.me/tags/social/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>running</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/running/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/running/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a reluctant runner for my whole life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a kid, we were forced to do cross-country training. Noone ever explained to me that running is supposed to be uncomfortable, and so I was terrible at it. Being terrible at something as a kid is a surefire way to hate it the rest of your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In late high-school I was overweight, and I took up some running to lose weight. It worked and I got down to a healthy weight (although still not &amp;lsquo;slim&amp;rsquo;). But I never got interested in running itself, and I doubt I surpassed 5km.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>cycling</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/cycling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/cycling/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve never had a strong interest in the &amp;lsquo;art of cycling&amp;rsquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ve never even watched a Tour de France stage. I like cycling because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Riding fast downhill is thrilling (while feeling relatively safe)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s good, low-impact exercise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It came to me at a time in life when I had forgotten how important hobbies are&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first two points are self-explanatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018 I had been focusing on my career to the exclusion of everything else. I slept on a mattress on the floor, owned very little, and had no hobbies. I would spend the weekend relaxing, drinking, socialising, playing the odd video game. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t a fulfilling life.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>sg60 trivia</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/sg60-trivia/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/sg60-trivia/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;2025 was Singapore&amp;rsquo;s 60th year since becoming an independent state. For a bit of fun with friends, I organised a trivia night centered around Singaporean culture and history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was learning to use Claude Code at the time, so instead of going with an existing trivia platform, I worked with Claude to build a locally hosted webapp which used websockets to take answers from players. Players would join the game by connecting to the server, and then use their phones to answer the questions. A main display of the question was shown on a different page and displayed on a projector. Finally I had a &amp;lsquo;host&amp;rsquo; screen on my laptop that I could use for admin tasks like changing question, changing scores, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>mahjong</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/mahjong/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/mahjong/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When I joined my cycling club in Singapore, I was required to join the entire social association surrounding it. This turned out to be great, as the association organises many activities and is full of great people. Through this association, I picked up casual mahjong games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The association plays the &amp;lsquo;British&amp;rsquo; version of Mahjong, which is not well known and I think quite different to any of the America/Chinese/Singaporean rules. To be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how representative it is of Mahjong in general, and I&amp;rsquo;m not confident that I have a good feel for &amp;lsquo;Mahjong&amp;rsquo; having only played this variant.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>tennis</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/tennis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/tennis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I had two major phases of playing tennis:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My parents took us to weekend tennis practice as kids&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some friends in Sydney needed a fourth for doubles, so I joined them for casual games and post-game drinks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a kid I had some minor amount of talent, but I never pursued it seriously. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember how long we took the weekend classes for, but it was at most a year or two.
There are some minor regrets here. While I don&amp;rsquo;t think tennis is a very well-designed sport (at least when it comes to playing for fun), I think it&amp;rsquo;s a great outlet for kids to learn about competition. Australia has a lot of infrastructure around it and a big tennis following and community. As someone who struggled to understand the mechanics of team sports, there&amp;rsquo;s a good chance that I&amp;rsquo;d have responded well to a competitive individual sport. And it likely would have helped the fact that I was an overweight kid too.
That being said, I don&amp;rsquo;t think our parents had a lot of money to put us through something like tennis lessons unless we showed some significant passion. I think this is a reasonable decision.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>basketball</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/basketball/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/basketball/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I had two major phases of playing basketball:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For a year in primary school I played in a local league for a year,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During university I frequently played casual games with friends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time in my primary school team went very similar to my time playing &lt;a href="https://timpieces.me/endeavours/afl/"&gt;AFL&lt;/a&gt;. Kids eh? Not much to say here but I remember being terrible in games, but really enjoying practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University gave me plenty of spare time, so I took to improving at shooting hoops. The games were much more casual, half-court, and often we&amp;rsquo;d just do shooting games. I got a lot of enjoyment out of this, and later in life when living near a basketball court I usually buy a basketball so that I can shoot hoops. I think my form is decent and I hope to live near a hoop again sometime soon.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>afl</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/afl/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/afl/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I played Aussie Rules Football (a.k.a. AFL = Australian Football League) for a year or two during primary school.
I don&amp;rsquo;t remember much about it besides that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any real talent for it. I started playing young, but a year or two behind others. This meant I had less in-game confidence which leads to getting the ball less which leads to less confidence and the spiral continues. I imagine that this is a common problem for kids in team sports. As a kid it&amp;rsquo;s hard to have the awareness to diagnose these types of problems.
On the plus side, I seemed to have plenty of out-of-game confidence, and the sport helped to develop my social skills. I remember having a positive time overall playing the sport because I enjoyed being around my team members.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>