<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Games on timpieces</title><link>https://timpieces.me/tags/games/</link><description>Recent content in Games on timpieces</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://timpieces.me/tags/games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>sg60 trivia</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/sg60-trivia/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/sg60-trivia/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;2025 was Singapore&amp;rsquo;s 60th year since becoming an independent state. For a bit of fun with friends, I organised a trivia night centered around Singaporean culture and history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was learning to use Claude Code at the time, so instead of going with an existing trivia platform, I worked with Claude to build a locally hosted webapp which used websockets to take answers from players. Players would join the game by connecting to the server, and then use their phones to answer the questions. A main display of the question was shown on a different page and displayed on a projector. Finally I had a &amp;lsquo;host&amp;rsquo; screen on my laptop that I could use for admin tasks like changing question, changing scores, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>mahjong</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/mahjong/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/mahjong/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When I joined my cycling club in Singapore, I was required to join the entire social association surrounding it. This turned out to be great, as the association organises many activities and is full of great people. Through this association, I picked up casual mahjong games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The association plays the &amp;lsquo;British&amp;rsquo; version of Mahjong, which is not well known and I think quite different to any of the America/Chinese/Singaporean rules. To be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how representative it is of Mahjong in general, and I&amp;rsquo;m not confident that I have a good feel for &amp;lsquo;Mahjong&amp;rsquo; having only played this variant.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>badminton</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/badminton/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/badminton/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When I moved to Singapore I wanted to put in a concerted effort to make some friends. Sports felt like a good way to do this, and choosing a popular local sport felt like a good way to make friends while integrating into the culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found a meetup group which organised games and you could pay to join. It was suitable for beginners. I did a single coached lesson to understand the basics and then I started playing.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>rust gameboy emulator</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/rust-gameboy-emulator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/rust-gameboy-emulator/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A confluence of factors led me to build a gameboy emulator in rust:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had some time off during 2022.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I felt motivated to learn rust. I was a professional C++ developer and learning rust felt like it would broaden my core skillset.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always been fascinated by emulators.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have very fond memories of playing pokemon blue as a child.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hadn&amp;rsquo;t written an emulator before, but the idea seemed mostly simply in principle. The great thing about the gameboy is how well documented it is. I remember using a combination of sources for the documentation but otherwise it was quite straightforward.
The goal was singular, to the to the point where I could play a full game of pokemon blue in the emulator. This meant that really all I needed was controls and the video display (i.e. no audio).
A lot of the time that went into this was:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>rocket league</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/rocket-league/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/rocket-league/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a little remiss to include Rocket League as an endeavour. It was a time in my life where I wasn&amp;rsquo;t very happy, and didn&amp;rsquo;t know how to be happy. The time was not well spent. It was very much an escape and way to avoid actually improving my life. But I figure it&amp;rsquo;s worth documenting something that I spent over 1000 hours on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I played multiplayer a handful of times in university and found the mechanics a lot of fun. I think that the game has a good balance of teamwork, mechanical skill (i.e. muscle memory and pushing buttons at the right time), and tactics. It&amp;rsquo;s skill curve keeps you addicted. Most importantly its short games meant you could iterate very quickly with quick feedback. In the same way as &lt;a href="https://timpieces.me/endeavours/chess/"&gt;chess&lt;/a&gt;, I got addicted to starting a game, winning or losing, and then immediately playing again to try to improve. As a result, I believe I cracked into Diamond league 1v1 before I stopped playing.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>chess</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/chess/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/chess/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I took up chess in university (approx 2014). My logic was exactly: &amp;ldquo;I could learn League Of Legends or Hearthstone, but if I learn chess then at least people will (falsely) assume I&amp;rsquo;m smart.&amp;rdquo; Given I wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting a huge difference in fun between the games, this felt like solid reasoning. Looking back, I still think it&amp;rsquo;s true. Noone respects people for spending 1000 hours on League of Legends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grinded many games on chess.com, watched many tutorials, read a few books.
After a year or two I got to around a 1700-ish +/- 100 rating in 10-minute time controls. This is a respectable level for an amateur who started as an adult without any formal training.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>silence of the lamb</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/silence-of-the-lamb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/silence-of-the-lamb/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="./silenceofthelamb.jpg" alt="Silence of the Lamb"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a university break, two friends and I decided to participate in a weekend game jam. The idea was that you sleep as little as you can and you build a game over 48 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some initial brainstorming, we settled on a game where you played as a lamb trying to escape a sacrifice. There was a procedurally generated world that you ran through, and you had to escape the tribespeople trying to catch you.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>starcraft 2</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/starcraft-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/starcraft-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Much of my high school evenings were spent playing starcraft 2. I don&amp;rsquo;t feel ashamed about it as I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like there was a high opportunity cost to this time. Not to say I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been doing better things, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t mature enough to actually be doing anything better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By far the most important thing that I learned from starcraft 2 was the competitive spirit. Not having done much sports up until this point, I had never felt very competitive. Starcraft 2 is the tightest competitive loop that one can experience. You start a game and play 1v1 for 20 minutes. You win or lose, then you start another game. There is some luck involved, but the game is mostly deterministic.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>padman</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/padman/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/padman/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="./padman.gif" alt="Padman"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In high school I was required to buy a Casio Classpad calculator. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember much about it besides that it had a CAS (which we were consistently told not to use&amp;hellip;) and could do some slow graphics rendering.
There were a handful of simple games available online for it, and I took it upon myself to build my own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the screen dimensions, I thought that pacman would be a good fit (literally). Through much trial and error, reading classpad documentation, and lurking on an online forum with some classpad programmers, I eventually got the game running.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>