<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Strategy on timpieces</title><link>https://timpieces.me/tags/strategy/</link><description>Recent content in Strategy on timpieces</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://timpieces.me/tags/strategy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>chess</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/chess/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/chess/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I took up chess in university (approx 2014). My logic was exactly: &amp;ldquo;I could learn League Of Legends or Hearthstone, but if I learn chess then at least people will (falsely) assume I&amp;rsquo;m smart.&amp;rdquo; Given I wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting a huge difference in fun between the games, this felt like solid reasoning. Looking back, I still think it&amp;rsquo;s true. Noone respects people for spending 1000 hours on League of Legends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grinded many games on chess.com, watched many tutorials, read a few books.
After a year or two I got to around a 1700-ish +/- 100 rating in 10-minute time controls. This is a respectable level for an amateur who started as an adult without any formal training.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>starcraft 2</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/starcraft-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/starcraft-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Much of my high school evenings were spent playing starcraft 2. I don&amp;rsquo;t feel ashamed about it as I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like there was a high opportunity cost to this time. Not to say I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been doing better things, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t mature enough to actually be doing anything better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By far the most important thing that I learned from starcraft 2 was the competitive spirit. Not having done much sports up until this point, I had never felt very competitive. Starcraft 2 is the tightest competitive loop that one can experience. You start a game and play 1v1 for 20 minutes. You win or lose, then you start another game. There is some luck involved, but the game is mostly deterministic.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>