<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sport on timpieces</title><link>https://timpieces.me/tags/sport/</link><description>Recent content in Sport on timpieces</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://timpieces.me/tags/sport/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>brazilian jiu jitsu</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/brazilian-jiu-jitsu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/brazilian-jiu-jitsu/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years I&amp;rsquo;d had many people get into BJJ. The way they talked about it led me to believe that there was &amp;lsquo;something to it&amp;rsquo;. As if it provides some physical enjoyment that is hard to explain in words. I found this was true of starting at the gym, and thought that BJJ might be similar (but perhaps with added adrenaline).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I signed up for a starter trial course at a local BJJ gym. The course was one month, and you could attend multiple times per week. I attended around six classes over the month.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>yoga</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/yoga/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/yoga/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I chose yoga because it was so different to any hobbies that I had tried before. Also, it was near my apartment.
Yoga Movement is a very commercial yoga chain in Singapore. I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of what they&amp;rsquo;ve done to commoditize yoga, as I&amp;rsquo;m not sold on the spiritual side of yoga. I downloaded their app and booked some classes.
I did the basic class many many times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without trying to sound bitter, yoga seems like an activity designed mostly for women&amp;rsquo;s bodies. They seem to have a much better level of default flexibility, which makes it much more enjoyable. It&amp;rsquo;s achievable for men (evidenced by the male yogis at the studio), but it seems to take much more effort.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>fencing</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/fencing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/fencing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In Singapore I live in a building which contains my gym. On the way to the gym I noticed a fencing club, so I decided to give it a shot. I messaged the number and after a few months they said they were organising an adult beginners course. I signed up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The class was foil. I diligently did my drills and learned my footwork. I did my parries and ripostes. We lunged&amp;hellip; a lot.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>skiing</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/skiing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/skiing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I tried skiing for 3 days in early 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally this would definitely not be enough to write about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only reason that I include it as an endeavour is that I&amp;rsquo;m very proud of having given it a shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think skiing is very difficult to learn as an adult, especially without dedicated lessons or a lot of time to spend on it. I joined some friends for 3 days in Japan and tried skiing with no instruction at all, and my friends were snowboarders. It went as poorly as you&amp;rsquo;d expect.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>badminton</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/badminton/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/badminton/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When I moved to Singapore I wanted to put in a concerted effort to make some friends. Sports felt like a good way to do this, and choosing a popular local sport felt like a good way to make friends while integrating into the culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found a meetup group which organised games and you could pay to join. It was suitable for beginners. I did a single coached lesson to understand the basics and then I started playing.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>bouldering</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/bouldering/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/bouldering/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I started bouldering with some friends and colleagues in Sydney towards the end of 2021. Some of them were strong boulderers and they were all great people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned some basic technique from youtube videos, and had an initial period of improving quickly. Still, I never bouldered enough to get past the beginner level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hated ripping skin off my fingers (as a full time software developer), everything else about the sport is quite enjoyable. The waiting around in bouldering is a good way to relax and take things slowly.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>tennis</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/tennis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/tennis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I had two major phases of playing tennis:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My parents took us to weekend tennis practice as kids&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some friends in Sydney needed a fourth for doubles, so I joined them for casual games and post-game drinks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a kid I had some minor amount of talent, but I never pursued it seriously. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember how long we took the weekend classes for, but it was at most a year or two.
There are some minor regrets here. While I don&amp;rsquo;t think tennis is a very well-designed sport (at least when it comes to playing for fun), I think it&amp;rsquo;s a great outlet for kids to learn about competition. Australia has a lot of infrastructure around it and a big tennis following and community. As someone who struggled to understand the mechanics of team sports, there&amp;rsquo;s a good chance that I&amp;rsquo;d have responded well to a competitive individual sport. And it likely would have helped the fact that I was an overweight kid too.
That being said, I don&amp;rsquo;t think our parents had a lot of money to put us through something like tennis lessons unless we showed some significant passion. I think this is a reasonable decision.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>basketball</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/basketball/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/basketball/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I had two major phases of playing basketball:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For a year in primary school I played in a local league for a year,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During university I frequently played casual games with friends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time in my primary school team went very similar to my time playing &lt;a href="https://timpieces.me/endeavours/afl/"&gt;AFL&lt;/a&gt;. Kids eh? Not much to say here but I remember being terrible in games, but really enjoying practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University gave me plenty of spare time, so I took to improving at shooting hoops. The games were much more casual, half-court, and often we&amp;rsquo;d just do shooting games. I got a lot of enjoyment out of this, and later in life when living near a basketball court I usually buy a basketball so that I can shoot hoops. I think my form is decent and I hope to live near a hoop again sometime soon.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>squash</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/squash/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/squash/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I played squash in my late teens, but just casually with my brother.
Normally I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t bother considering this as an endeavour worth mentioning, except that it&amp;rsquo;s a sport that I&amp;rsquo;ve since had occasion to play casually quite a few times.
I played with a friend during university, and colleagues at multiple workplaces.
I&amp;rsquo;ve never had any formal training, but I&amp;rsquo;ve got enough of the basics to play a decent game.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>afl</title><link>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/afl/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timpieces.me/endeavours/afl/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I played Aussie Rules Football (a.k.a. AFL = Australian Football League) for a year or two during primary school.
I don&amp;rsquo;t remember much about it besides that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any real talent for it. I started playing young, but a year or two behind others. This meant I had less in-game confidence which leads to getting the ball less which leads to less confidence and the spiral continues. I imagine that this is a common problem for kids in team sports. As a kid it&amp;rsquo;s hard to have the awareness to diagnose these types of problems.
On the plus side, I seemed to have plenty of out-of-game confidence, and the sport helped to develop my social skills. I remember having a positive time overall playing the sport because I enjoyed being around my team members.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>